Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- David Wiliams (b. 1955)
  David Williams first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain an artist's biography, an artist's statement, and correspondence. These materials are dated 2002.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-williams
  - Box 65, Folder 7 (Box 65)
- Remerro "Trotsky" Williams (b. 1953)
  Remerro "Trotsky" Williams was born in 1953 in Washington, DC. His father and grandfather were both painters, inspiring a love of art from a young age. He studied at the School of Visual Arts in New York and at Hoch Schuler der Kunste in West Berlin. He spent time in New York, Berlin, Paris, and London. His paintings have been shown in the US and internationally and are held in various private collections.
  Remerro "Trotsky" Williams first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain correspondence, press clippings, photocopies of artworks, photographs, an artist's biography, a CV, Postcards from the Edge submission materials and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1986-2018.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/remerro-trotsky
  - Box 65, Folder 8 (Box 65)
- Albert Winn (1947–2014)
  Albert Winn was born in 1947 in Chester, Pennsylvania. He studied housing and urban studies, urban planning, and art throughout his education, receiving a BS, an MA, and an MFA. His autobiographical photography work addresses Judaism, gender, and sexuality in the context of illness and memory. It has been exhibited in New York, California, Massachusetts, and internationally. He passed away in 2014.
  Albert Winn first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain CVs, artist's biographies, ephemera, project proposals, exhibition text, artist's statements, correspondence, essays, publications, photographic prints of art, periodicals, and CDs with images of art, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1989-2010.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/albert-winn
  - Box 66, Folder 1 (Box 66)
  - Box 66, Folder 2 (Box 66)
  - Box 66, Folder 3 (Box 66)
  - Box C, Folder 4 (Box C)
- Bruce Witsiepe (1951–1995)
  Bruce Witsiepe was born in 1951. He studied art at the Louisville School of Art and Cooper Union. His work includes sculpture, mixed media work, and performance. He exhibited primarily in New York and his work is held in collections internationally. He passed away in 1995.
  Materials pertaining to Bruce Witsiepe were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000 by Tony Pinotti. They contain photographic prints of art, correspondence, a CV, collection of poetry, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1992-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/bruce-witsiepe
  - Box 66, Folder 4 (Box 66)
- David Wojnarowicz (1954–1992)
  David Wojnarowicz was born in 1954 in Red Bank, New Jersey. He dropped out of high school and hitchhiked across the US before settling in the East Village in 1978. He was a painter, photographer, writer, filmmaker, performance artist, and activist. He was prominent in the New York City art world in the 1980s and was very active politically after his AIDS diagnosis in the late 80s. He participated in public debates about medical research and funding, morality and censorship in the arts, and the legal rights of artists. He is the author of five books, and has artwork in numerous private and public collections, including MoMA and the Whitney. He passed away in 1992.
  Materials pertaining to David Wojnarowicz were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Thomas Rauffenbert. They contain exhibition announcements, publications, exhibition programs, CVs, press releases, press clippings, exhibition catalogs, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1983-2018.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-wojnarowicz
  - Box 66, Folder 5 (Box 66)
  - Box 67, Folder 1 (Box 67)
  - Box 67, Folder 2 (Box 67)
- Steven Wolf (b. 1948)
  Steven Wolf was born in 1948 in Johnstown, Pennsylvania. He received an MA in sculpture and an MFA in painting from West Virginia University. He works in painting and illustration, and has exhibited in Virginia, North Carolina, and New York.
  Steven Wolf first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain exhibition announcements, artwork on postcards, correspondence, CVs, artist's statements, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1999-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/steven-wolf
  - Box 67, Folder 3 (Box 67)
- Martin Wong (1946–1999)
  Martin Wong was born in 1946 in Portland, Oregon. He was a painter whose meticulous visionary realism is among the lasting legacies of New York's East Village art scene of the 1980s and a precursor of the identity-driven work of the 90s. He was passionate about painting, calligraphy, antiques, and graffiti. His collection of over 300 works on graffiti was donated to the Museum of the City of New York. His work was exhibited widely in New York and across the US. He passed away in 1999.
  Martin Wong first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition catalogs, CVs, press clippings, exhibition announcements, exhibition programs, handwritten pieces, correspondence, ephemera, memorial materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1982-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/martin-wong
  - Box 67, Folder 4 (Box 67)
- Darrell Wood (b. 1956)
  Darrell Wood was born in 1956 in Greenville, Mississippi. He was classically trained as a ballet dancer and published poetry from the age of 17. He has worked as a graphic designer and web designer. He works primarily in painting and has exhibited in New York.
  Darrell Wood first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain an artist's biography and grant submission materials. These materials are dated 2002.
  - Box 67, Folder 5 (Box 67)
- William M. Wood (1972–2016)
  William M. Wood III was born in 1972 in Reading, Pennsylvania. He received a BA in psychology from the University of Texas. He studied ceramics, drawing, photography, and painting at schools and workshops around the country. His work has been exhibited in North and South Carolina. He passed away in 2016.
  William M Wood first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain a CD with images of art and a CV. These materials are dated 2009.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/william-wood
  - Box 67, Folder 6 (Box 67)
- Peter Wyman (1958–2018)
  Peter Wyman was born in 1958 in Providence, Rhode Island. He received a BA from Duke University and studied painting, printmaking, glassblowing, and calligraphy from various other institutions. His work includes painting, prints, and collage. It has been exhibited in widely in Florida and along the east coast.
  Peter Wyman first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2005. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, copies of artwork, CDs with images of artwork with accompanying image list, CVs, press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1996-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/peter-wyman
  - Box 67, Folder 7 (Box 67)
- Rev. Yolanda aka Roger Anthony Mapes (b. 1960)
  Rev. Yolanda (Roger Anthony Mapes) was born in 1960 in Muscle Shoals, Alabama. She is an accomplished, award-winning singer/songwriter, performance artist, visual artist, and interfaith minister. She was inducted into the GLBT Hall of Fame for Activism, Art, Excellence, and Community Awareness in 2005. A feature film about her life was released in June 2015.
  Rev Yolanda (Roger Anthony Mapes) first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain a CV, an artist's statement, press clippings, exhibition announcements, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1998-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/rev.-yolanda
  - Box 68, Folder 2 (Box 68)
- Laurence Young (b. 1952)
  Laurence Young was born in 1952 in Boston, Massachusetts. He received a BA in Art Education from Hartford Art School and an MFA in Printmaking from Rhode Island School of Design. His work is primarily in painting and has been exhibited widely along the east coast. He lives and works in Provincetown, Massachusetts.
  Laurence Young first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain photographic prints, ephemera, CDs with images of art with accompanying image lists, exhibition announcements, correspondence, press clippings, CVs, artist's statements, image lists, calendar submission materials, an artist's biography, publications, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1992-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/laurence-young
  - Box 68, Folder 3 (Box 68)
  - Box 68, Folder 4 (Box 68)
- Kurt Zager (Schwerdtfeger) (b. 1965)
  Kurt Zager (Schwerdtfeger) was born in 1965 in Margaretville, New York. As an adult, he studied at the New York Academy of Art. His paintings are primarily of nature and have been exhibited in New York.
  Kurt Zager (Schwerdtfeger) first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain an artist's biography. These materials are dated 1999.
  - Box 68, Folder 6 (Box 68)
- Tal Zargarhof (1961–2015)
  Tal Zargarhof was born in 1961 in Israel. He was privately tutored for 10 years in pop art by artist Rom Gotfried. He moved to the US in 1984 and had six successful shows in New York. His artwork includes acrylic paintings, illustration, photography, and fabric design. He passed away in 2015.
  Tal Zargarhof first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain correspondence, artist's biographies, images of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2002-2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tal-zargarhof
  - Box 68, Folder 9 (Box 68)
- Andrew Zealley (b. 1956)
  Andrew Zealley was born in 1956. He received an MFA from Ontario College of Art and Design University and a PhD through the Faculty of Environment and Urban Change (EUC) at York University in Toronto, Ontario. His artwork is organized around sound and listening practices and media including music, video, photography, bookmaking, pedagogy, and activism. He is based in Toronto, Canada.
  Materials pertaining to Andrew Zealley include an event program. This material is dated 2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/andrew-zealley
  - Box 70, Folder 12 (Box 70)
- Jeff Zimmer (b. 1970)
  Jeff Zimmer was born in 1970 in Minot, North Dakota. He was trained in theatre in Washington, DC before moving to Edinburgh, Scotland to obtain his masters in glass painting. His work is in the permanent collection of various museums in the UK and Europe. He teaches and works in Edinburgh.
  Jeff Zimmer first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain a CV and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2002-2004.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jeff-zimmer
  - Box 68, Folder 10 (Box 68)
- Zion Kyakulaga and Grace Talitwala Collective (b. 1972)
  Zion Kyakulaga and Grace Talitwala are artists who formed an art collective from Uganda. Working with natural materials, such as banana fiber and tree bark, they create works that reflect their experience with HIV/AIDS. They mentor young artists in Uganda.
  Zion Kyakulaga and Grace Talitwala first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000 as a collective. They contain an exhibit catalog, correspondence, calendar submission materials, a biography, and photographic prints. These materials are dated 1999-2001.
  - Box 68, Folder 11 (Box 68)